Breath of the Beast.
Seventh Fang, Spatial Awareness.
Did you find it?
Yes, it's over there.
I can sense
that they're incredibly strong.
You're awesome, Inosuke.
Damn.
I'll have to deal with these people
if I want to go forth.
Damn.
Is there no way out of this?
Nezuko...
Where are you?
Damn it!
What a pain in the ass.
I'm going to send them flying in one blow.
No, don't even think about it!
We have to think of something
so we don't have to hurt them.
Mr. Murata.
Leave this to me. You guys go ahead.
Who are you kidding, Pissed-my-pants?
Who are you calling Pissed-my-pants,
you stupid pig?
I wasn't even talking to you, so shut up!
I'm sorry that I've given you
such a bad impression,
but I'm still a Demon Slayer.
I'll do my best to stand my ground.
I know that I just have
to cut those web strings.
It's not so hard to predict
how they're used as puppets.
I'll look out for the spiders too.
When a demon is around,
it will probably puppet someone stronger.
You two go now!
I got it. Thank you!
Let's go, Inosuke.
Let go of me!
I want to beat him up first!
Who's a stupid pig?
Shut up!
Take your ramblings out of here!
I'll be back to beat you up!
Damn, I will totally beat him up.
Stop talking about that.
He called me a stupid pig, Monjiro.
It's Tanjiro!
By the way, is this the right way?
My senses never betrayed me.
But...
What are these annoying threads
doing here?
It shows that the demon is upon us.
There's another one coming.
No.
Don't get past here.
Go back and get the higher ranks here.
If not, I'll get you all killed!
Please.
Please!
I wonder if you'll be able to beat this.
The closer you are to me,
the thicker and tougher the threads,
and the harder the puppets are to fight.
Mom.
Can you win this?
Rui.
It seems that you've wasted a lot of time.
If you don't finish them now,
I'll tell Dad about this.
It's okay. I got this covered.
I'll protect you.
So leave your dad out of this.
Don't tell your dad.
Your dad...
Then, finish the job.
Die, die!
Die now!
Otherwise, I'll be in big trouble.
Run!
That's fast.
They caught me in their strings,
so my moves are totally abnormal.
We were never this strong to begin with.
As they're controlled by demons
like puppets,
they can still fight
even with broken bones.
This is outrageous.
This is one tough nut to crack.
But then again...
What's that noise?
Kill...
Kill us now.
My limbs are broken.
I could feel my bones
stabbing into my guts.
They turned me into a puppet.
I can't take these sharp pains anymore.
We're heading for our doom anyway.
Help me.
Put me out of this misery.
Sure thing!
Wait!
Wait a second.
There must be a way to save them.
Stop being so fussy.
You're such a fusspot!
But...
You heard him say
to put him out of his misery.
They're so fast.
If we don't finish this soon,
we'll end up in shreds.
I know.
I'm thinking of a way, so please wait.
I don't want to attack them.
But even if I cut them off,
they'll string them up again.
I have to stop that from happening.
I got it!
Hey!
Good, she's coming for me.
Why are you running in circles?
Fooling around at a time like this?
Total Concentration.
What great power.
Good, she's hung nicely.
What...
What was that?
I want to try it too!
Did you see that?
If you can do it, so can I.
Sorry, I didn't.
What?
I was too busy for that!
Damn.
All those puppets have failed me.
Now it's all down to that puppet.
Nezuko!
Nezuko, where are you?
Nezuko.
Tanjiro.
Wild boar.
Chuntaro.
Where are you guys?
It's all my fault.
Chuntaro.
Did you come here for me?
You're such a cute little friend,
although you're not as cute as Nezuko.
It's all my fault.
Okay, let's go find Nezuko.
Hey, look!
Can you see there?
Mine is higher than yours.
Yes, there's one left.
Right, I'll show you one last time,
so don't miss it.
Sure, go ahead.
But don't get too rough.
I don't need feeble human puppets.
Humans are useless!
Damn, she killed everyone.
Let's go.
You're right.
This way.
We're getting really close.
The wind is changing.
My keen sense of smell is coming back.
That way, we'll know where the demon is.
There are two scents here.
Inosuke!
I found it first.
I will chop off its head!
This guy...
He's headless!
Where are you, Nezuko?
Where have you run to,
Tanjiro and Inosuke?
Don't leave me alone
in this terrifying forest.
What?
I'm getting really mad.
I have to find Nezuko
and leave this scary forest fast.
Nezuko!
He has no weak spots.
We can't behead him.
Inosuke.
What should we do?
Calm down and do a kesagiri.
Cut on the right shoulder
and out through the left armpit.
It's a wide range,
and it's probably rock solid.
Wait, let's do it together!
He's fast.
But I can still dodge him!
Crap, it's a spider!
I can't move.
I'm getting hacked!
Inosuke, we're in this battle together.
Let's think of a way to beat this demon.
Let's fight him together.
Damn you!
Stop making me frizzy all over!
Get out of my way!
Inosuke, tread on me!
Inosuke, jump!
Total Concentration Breathing.
Breath of Water.
Fourth Form.
Striking Tide!
Do a kesagiri!
Damn, this guy is getting into my nerves.
I had to follow his orders all the time.
As if everything is predetermined.
As a matter of course like a river flow.
He doesn't make his moves spontaneously,
but he's observing
the whole course of the fight.
Great, he slashed it.
You did it.
You defeated him, Inosuke.
Inosuke?
If you can do it,
so can I, you idiot!
This smell...
I see what you mean, Inosuke.
I lost.
I'm defeated.
That was my strongest, fastest puppet.
If it weren't for Rui threatening me,
I wouldn't have been
so anxious and jittery.
Up there.
Breath of Water, First Form.
I'm finished!
He's after my head.
Quick, think of something.
But...
If I die, I'll be free.
I can untie myself from all this.
Fifth Form,
Blessed Rain After the Drought.
What is this?
It feels like a tender spell of rain
showering over me.
It doesn't hurt a bit.
It's not painful at all.
I only feel warmth.
I didn't know I could greet death
in such a serene manner.
Thus, I'm unbound.
It's all my fault. I apologize.
Please forgive me!
Why are you angry at me?
What did I do wrong?
Your mistake is not knowing
why he is angry.
How can that be? I'm just--
Mom made Dad angry again.
No.
No! Please, don't!
That look.
It's so gentle.
When I was a human,
I think someone gazed at me
with such a gentle look.
Who was it?
I can't remember.
But I think that person
has always cherished me.
I wonder what he or she is up to.
The Twelve Demon Moons are here.
Wait!
You must be careful.
The Twelve Demon Moons are here.
The real Twelve Demon Moons
are on this mountain.
If you can do it, so can I.
But I know that you're bad at one thing.
What was that?
You can't even remember my name, can you?
Of course I remember your name.
You're Gonpachiro Kamaboko!
Wrong.
-Gengoro Shakariki.
-No.
-Tontaro Itadaki.
-That's way off.
Here's a little gossip
from the Taisho era.
I heard that Inosuke gets others' names
right once every seven times.
You got my name wrong three times.
Can you really nail it?
Kanjiro Anago!
You're getting close.
Tangoro Hamado.
A little off.
Janjiro Amado!
Just a little more!
Tanjiro...
It doesn't really matter
what your name is.
You almost got my full name.
Next, episode 17,
"You Must Master a Single Thing."
You do your own thing and I do mine.
You get that, Tanjiro?
TO BE CONTINUED
Subtitle translation by CL Tan